2x18 - New Recruit
Removing Bumblebee
and replacing him with...
[ beep ]
[ monkey screeches ]
The tap-dancing monkey
strikes again.
[ beep ]
Bumblebee sightings on the
world wide web are no laughing matter.
[ grunts ]
7...
8... 9...
[ grunts ]
[ sighs ] Why can't I
just drive from now on?
Because your legs will
atrophy if you choose not to use them.
[ moans ]
1...
[ grunts ]
2...
3...
[ moans ]
Wait. What's that?
[ click, beeping ]
A Cybertronian escape pod?
Here in Earth's atmosphere?
[ beeping ]
Autobot or Decepticon?
Impossible to tell,
given the image resolution.
In any event,
this merits investigation.
Could be a trap,
and we're down one bot.
- Should we reach out to Wheeljack?
- I can hear you!
I don't care if Bulkhead
isn't combat-ready.
After that revenge stunt he pulled
with Miko, Wheeljack can stay rogue.
An Autobot may be in distress.
Ratchet, bring your medical kit.
- It is of Decepticon origin.
- And the Con inside blew his way out.
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ addic7ed.com ~
All those Cons came out of one pod?
The humans refer to the
phenomenon as a clown car.
[ grunts ]
[ screams ]
[ squeals ]
- Incoming!
- Down in front!
Friendly?
Fall back!
Whoo!
Two hot for you, Cons?!
Friend of yours?
[ beeping ]
Never seen him before.
Torching that Energon leak ...
pretty good plan, right?
Except that it wasn't your plan.
It was a random shot that
almost fried us to a crisp.
- Worked out, didn't it?
- Thank you, fellow Autobot.
Your... valor...
is to be commended.
I... don't believe it.
Y-You're Optimus Prime!
He's Optimus Prime!
- We know.
- Yes, yes...
[ beeping ]
- What is your name, soldier?
- Smokescreen, sir.
Welcome to Earth, Smokescreen.
It's an honor to be here...
especially with you.
Now what? It's not like we can
just bring him back to base.
Wouldn't be the first time
an ally turned out to be a plant.
I see that you received your
training from Cybertron's elite guard.
True enough ...
though it wasn't more than
a boot camp by the time I joined.
I never even got a proper
graduation ceremony.
There was a war going on.
Hey, all I ever wanted was to be
a soldier, serve the Autobot cause.
But what I got was
security detail at Iacon.
The Hall of Records of all places?
Optimus, do you not find
this highly suspicious?
Smokescreen, what was your
assignment inside the hall?
Guarding Alpha Trion during what turned
out to be the final days of the war.
- You served under the master archivist?
- Eh, I wasn't thrilled at first ...
watching the back of an old bot
instead of kicking Con tailpipe.
Sorry. But the big "A" turned out
to be a great teacher and a... true friend.
I mean, he was the one
who petitioned Halogen
and the High Council
to make you a Prime.
Rafael... activate the ground bridge.
That's it?
That's all you need to hear
before inviting him to the party?
If my former mentor shared
this information, it is because
he considered Smokescreen
a trusted ally.
We haven't had somebody
new here since Wheeljack.
What's your story, Smoke?
Where'd you come from?
How'd you get here?
How many blasters you packin'?
So, these are the life-force
we're supposed to protect?
- Are they all like this?
- Fortunately not...
but I too share Miko's fascination
with how you came to arrive on Earth.
In a Decepticon escape pod.
Still got trust issues, huh?
Tough crowd.
The main thrust of combat
operations was at least 20 clicks
from the Hall of Records,
so things had been pretty quiet.
But the situation went downhill fast.
The Cons launched a massive
surge that wiped out the last
line of defenses surrounding Iacon.
I was the only thing left to them back,
and, let me tell you, I was pumped.
I mean, this was my chance to see real
action for the first time ... to prove myself.
Until everything went black.
Cons took me prisoner and
dumped me onto a transport ship.
[ electricity crackling ]
But I managed to give a guard the
slip and hopped in an escape pod.
Apparently, it was a long-distance pod,
'cause it knocked me into stasis.
Next thing I knew,
I'm hitting solid ground ... hard.
The Decepticon warship must have picked
up pod's beacon and guided it to Earth.
Which would explain
Smokescreen's welcoming committee.
[ scoffs ]
Bet those Cons were disappointed
not to find one of their own inside.
Smokescreen, do you know of
Alpha Ttrion's fate, after the fall of Iacon?
I wish I did. But that was
the last I ever saw of him.
That's it ...  my life story.
Not exactly the glory I
envisioned for myself... until now.
Being here with Optimus Prime ...
I knew I was destined for great things.
I mean, now that you have help,
how hard could it be to end this war?
[ grunts ]
[ groaning, gasping ]
Take a good look, Newbie.
This is how hard.
Smokescreen, I would suggest
that you take some time
to become acclimated
to your new surroundings.
A tour of the base would
be an excellent start.
Sure thing!
[ groans ]
I mean... Jack here offers
a very informative tour.
This is what the humans call
"the information superhighway."
A trillion gigabytes of data ...
none of it's useful!
[ computer whirring ]
[ beeping ]
[ monkey screeches ]
Though some oddly engrossing.
[ chuckles ]
What is this?
Ah...
[laughs]
ignorant life-forms have no
idea what they've uncovered.
Red Energon.
If I can possess its power, not only
will I be stronger but also faster.
Significantly faster.
Phase shifter...
Spark extractor...
immobilizer...
this is where we store the
Cybertronian relics we
found buried on Earth.
And talk about a small universe
'cause most of them came from the ...
The Iacon hall of records.
I remember these.
Whoa.
What kind of relic is she?
The kind you don't want to mess with.
If you wanted to replace me,
you should have called Wheeljack.
- I could have lived with that.
- No one is replacing you, Bulkhead.
For one thing,
Smokescreen's too green.
- Well, Bulk's as green as they get.
- What Arcee means is...
Smokescreen still has
a great deal to learn.
And once you got him
trained, then what, huh?
He's in.
I'm a doorstop.
Bulkhead, your place with us
is not in jeopardy, but there is
no dispute that we have long
required additional firepower.
It is essential that
our team learns to work
with our new recruit,
not against him.
Better hope the hotshot's
blasters are as big as his mouth.
- How hard can it be?
- Hey, everyone. Check this out.
[ beeping ]
But don't tell me it's another
Bumblebee sight... oh my.
- Red Energon.
- Here... on Earth?
What's Red Energon?
An extremely rare and
volatile form of Energellum.
Refined into fuel, it provides
the power of hyperspeed.
We must have Agent Fowler clear
the dig site of all human presence
in the event we are not the only
ones who have discovered its location.
Now you're talking.
Let's scramble up some Cons' circuits.
Given your limited field
experience, I believe further
training is required
before you are battle-ready.
Optimus, with all due respect ...
Furthermore, we Autobots live on
this planet as robots in disguise.
You will need to obtain
an Earth-based vehicle mode.
In order to maintain a low profile...
if that's possible for you.
If you're talking wheels,
bring 'em on!
The Red Energon is mine, humans!
For you are powerless in the
face of the mighty star...
What?
Where is it?
Nope.
How about that one?
Eh, it's more Ratchet's speed,
don't you think?
- Cement truck?
- Yeah, if I were a Constructicon.
Seriously, this is the best
your planet has to offer?
- No, but this is Jasper.
- I feel for you.
Fowler couldn't have the
crane operator lower the thing?
The humans must have been
preparing to transfer the meteor
to a cargo ship when they
received his evacuation order.
Run along home, Autobots.
That Red Energon has
my name all over it.
And I am more
than willing to fight for it.
Secure the Red Energon and have
Ratchet bridge it back to base.
Don't tell me you've already
forgotten our last encounter, Prime.
Keep moving, B.
Optimus, is something wrong?
Starscream has come for the Red Energon,
and I fear he will not
be deterred in his quest.
Starscream?
I heard stories about that
stiletto-heeled creep back on Cybertron.
Send me in, Doc.
When Optimus requires
backup, he will ask for it.
Aw, come on.
I got my V-mode and everything.
- I'm souped up and ready to roll.
- Eh! Eh! Eh!
What part of "further training"
did you not understand?
The higher you climb,
the harder you fall.
[ laughs ]
Autobots ...
such slow learners.
Optimus, what is your status?
Ratchet, they need me.
I can do this.
Arcee? Bumblebee?
[ static ]
- Did you hear what I said?
- I heard, and I'm ignoring you.
This may be your opportunity
after all, Smokescre...
Where is Smokescreen?
- That's the one.
- You, there!
What in the name of the Allspark
do you think you're doing?
Time to unload some more deadweight.
[ screams ]
[ grunting ]
No!
[ screams ]
[ crash ]
[ growls ]
Watch your step, Autobots!
[ laughs evilly ]
Huh?
Apparently, no one defined
"low profile" for him.
So, the Autobots have a new recruit.
And you must be Starscream.
I thought you'd be taller.
[ growls ]
- This will not end well.
- Smokescreen, stand down.
You are no match for
Starscream's Apex armor.
Any last words, Smokescreen?
Just four ...
kiss your armor goodbye.
[ warbling ]
[ grunts ]
- A Phase shifter?
- Now, that was a plan!
[ sighs ]
You aren't the only one sporting
a fancy wrist-mounted device.
Think fast!
No!
Told you I just needed
to borrow it for a while.
Doc here thought I was
trying to steal your relics.
Only until you explained your
plan, which I then sanctioned.
It's called protocol.
Ratchet is correct.
Standard procedure must be
observed by every member of this team.
However...
I believe we must also
commend Smokescreen.
You have proven to be a quick study
by choosing to place
strategy above bravado.
There is gonna be no
living with him now.
While this may lack
the pageantry of a proper elite
guard ceremony, I wish to
welcome you to team Prime.
[ grunts ]
The Newbie did all right.
Don't worry, Bulk.
He's got nothing on you.
Seriously, once we get that
leg of yours back in shape,
old Smokey's gonna learn real quick
who the top wrecking ball is run here.
Bulkhead?
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ addic7ed.com ~