Previously on Transformers Prime...
Bulkhead, prepare for departure.
Raphael and Agent Fowler
will be your communications
and transportation hub.
- Who is the fiercest among you?
- I am Hardshell.
You will retrieve
something for me. Tox-En.
You're carrying it?
I thought that stuff was toxic.
Your Spark is mine, Wrecker.
That's right, soldier.
Come on home!
The Wrecker left me alive.
The last mistake he will ever make.
No!
2x16 - Hurt
Oh, yeah!
Hey!
Let me guess ...  you and Raf spend all
your drive time listening to chip tunes.
Well, it's been fun, but I'm
ready to get back to my
regularly scheduled partner,
Bulkhe...  aah!
Bulkhead, respond!
Bulkhead?
sync & correction by f1nc0
~ addic7ed.com ~
Bulkhead?
What happened?
Tox-En exposure, among other things.
Bulkhead has suffered a
complete systems failure.
Hold on. Tox-En?
Help me get him into the
medical bay... now!
No!
If I hadn't gone to New York ...
There's nothing you could
have done!
Hardshell sucker-punched the
big lug while he was down.
KOnec